photonics.com 2018-08-13

# Privacy Notice | Photonics.com

Effective Date: 7/5/2018 

Laurin Publishing Co, Inc. is firmly committed to protecting your privacy. We want you to make an informed decision about sharing personal data with us, and this privacy notice explains what personal data we collect from you and how we use that data. 

You can contact us at [privacy@photonics.com](mailto:privacy@photonics.com) with any questions or comments about this privacy notice or our privacy practices. 

## SUMMARY OF OUR PRIVACY PRACTICES

  * ### Personal Data Collection

We collect information you choose to share with us, as well as information sent to us by your browser or provided to us by third parties. Categories of information collected include: 
    * Basic contact information
    * Billing information
    * Subscription and registration information
    * Website navigation and traffic information
  
Learn more about our data collection practices. 
  * ### Personal Data Use

We use your information for the purposes of providing you with information and services you request, improving the delivery of services and functionality of our websites, customizing your experience with us, sending marketing and other communications related to our business, and protecting our website. 

Learn more about our data use practices. 

  * ### Personal Data Disclosure

We disclose the least amount of personal information that is necessary to accomplish a specific purpose or where you have provided consent. In some circumstances, we share data with vendors or agents working on our behalf for the purposes described in this notice, such as supporting subscription services, web hosting and analytics, and processing purchase payments. 

Where we have your consent, we will also share your personal data with advertisers and marketers. When you interact with content provided by or about our advertisers, we will share limited demographic information with our advertisers, but this information does not include your name or contact information. We also share anonymous, aggregate information about our users with our advertisers, but this information cannot reasonably be traced back to you. 

Learn more about our data disclosure practices. 

## INTRODUCTION

Our privacy notice applies to any user of our website. 

Our users access news, information, products, content, and events related to the high-tech field of photonics (optics, lasers, imaging, fiber, etc.). Content and data on some areas of our website is only viewable by member account holders. 

This privacy notice applies to all users of our website, Photonics.com. 

We determine the purpose and means of processing your personal data. 

Laurin Publishing is the "controller" of your personal data, which means we determine the purpose and means of processing your personal data. This privacy notice explains those purposes and means to you, and you have choices over the collection and use of your data. 

As a user of our websites, the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal data is subject to this privacy notice and any subsequent updates. 

## LAWFULNESS OF PERSONAL DATA PROCESSING

We only process your data when we have a legal basis to do so. 

We only collect and use your personal data when we have a lawful basis to do so. Legal bases include your consent (you have granted us permission to use your personal data) and situations where processing is necessary to fulfill a contractual obligation, such as providing services you request. 

We process your data when you give us permission to do so. 

When you grant us permission to use your data for a specific, articulated purpose, we will process your data. We ask for consent to send you our publications and marketing materials, to participate in our interactive features, and to share your contact information with our advertising partners. 

Where we rely on your consent for processing, you have the right to change, withdraw, or withhold your consent. 

We process your data to fulfill our obligations to you. 

In some circumstances, we process your data to fulfill our obligation to you, including to respond to a request or communication from you and to complete a purchase you made. 

We process your data when it is in our legitimate interest to do so, except where such processing is outweighed by your rights and freedoms. 

As part of our ongoing business operations, we may process your personal data based on our legitimate interest or the legitimate interest of a third party (e.g., your employer or company), except were such interests are outweighed by your rights and freedoms. 

Our legitimate interests include: 

  * Investigating, preventing, and protecting against fraud, security risks, threats to you and others, and violations of this policy
  * Verifying your identity and qualification for a free subscription
  * Protecting and defending our rights and properties, including intellectual property
  * Complying with laws and regulations that apply to us, as well as responding to requests from law enforcement or government authorities or as otherwise required by law
  * Understanding and improving our website, user experience, and customer relationships
  * Enabling our business operations

## WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT

We collect personal data you share with us directly, as well as information shared by your web browser and third parties. 

We collect personal data you knowingly choose to disclose to us. "Personal data" is information that can be used to individually identify you. We also collect information that is sent to us automatically by your web browser when you view and navigate our website, as well as information provided to us by third parties. 

## Personal Data You Provide to Us

You provide personal data to create an account with us. 

### Account Management

When you register a member account, you will be asked to provide basic contact information, including your name, company, address, telephone and fax numbers, and email address. As part of your account, we will ask you to create a user name and provide a password. 

We collect this information for the purpose of providing you with access to certain features on our websites or services you request. Maintaining a member account also makes it easier for you to register for webinars, access member-only exclusive content, download white papers, and request information by prepopulating submission forms with your contact information, which you may edit before sending for these purposes. 

Registering an account is voluntary, and we collect your personal data only upon your consent when you submit the registration form. You can withdraw your consent and cancel your account at any time by contacting us at [privacy@photonics.com](mailto:privacy@photonics.com) with your request. 

You provide billing information for purchases. 

### Purchase Fulfillment

To process an order made through our bookstore, we will collect basic contact and billing information, including name, address, telephone number, and if applicable fax number, email address, and payment information. We collect this information for the purpose of completing our transaction with you. We will only collect this information if you initiate a purchase through our bookstore. If you do not complete your purchase, we will retain the information you have input to allow you to easily return and complete your purchase at a later time. 

You provide data to receive publications and communications. 

### Subscription and Communication Management

If you choose to subscribe to our newsletters and publications, we will ask you to submit your name, company, address, telephone and fax numbers, and email address. 

We use this information for the purpose of delivering requested copies of our content. Delivery of our newsletter and publication content directly to you does require your contact information, but you can manage your communication preferences as described in this section under "Manage Your Communication Preferences." 

As part of registering for our free subscriptions, we also collect information about your employment, such as job title and technologies and products you work with. We use this information to verify that you are eligible for a free subscription, as well as to provide you with additional communications regarding information we think you may find interesting. When we collect this information, we ask for your consent to use this information for marketing purposes. You can change, withdraw, or withhold your consent at any time by managing your communication preferences. 

If you contact us directly, such as to request information on advertising rates or order copies of our publications, your communications with us may include your contact information. In such circumstances, we only collect your contact information when you initiate contact with us. 

### You can manage your communication preferences in several ways:

  * Photonics.com members can login and manage their print and newsletter subscriptions here
  * Click the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of our communications
  * Click here and follow the instructions to manage your email preferences
  * Contact us at [privacy@photonics.com](mailto:privacy@photonics.com) to request to be removed from a subscription list

You provide data when you submit material for publication. 

### Content Submitted for Publication

When you choose to submit articles, white papers, press or product releases, event listings, videos, or other material to be considered for publication on our website or in our magazines, you will be asked to provide your name, phone number, and email address, which we may use to follow up with you regarding publication. When we choose to publish the content you submit, we will publish the contact information you provided as part of your submission to allow readers to contact you to request more information. When you choose to submit a company listing for publication in the Photonics Buyers' Guide, you will be asked to provide your company contact information, a description of business products and capabilities, the contact information of key personnel, including email address, and other company demographics. 

Please note that information you submit for publication can be viewed by anyone who subscribes to our print publications or accesses our website. Some information for the Buyers’ Guide is only collected for aggregate demographics about the industry and markets, and those fields are marked as such. Do not submit any information you do not want published publicly or used for these purposes. 

You provide data to facilitate your participation in special events. 

### Interactive Feature Participation

You may also choose to participate in different interactive features we offer. We only collect this information for the purpose of facilitating your participation in our interactive features. 

### Comment Sections

To leave a comment on our website, you must create a member account. We require the use of an account to minimize unwanted spam and to ensure the comment sections of our website remain a pleasant experience for all our users. 

When you choose to leave a comment on an article, we will access your member account or ask you to login to your account to enable the comments feature. We will collect and display your username and the content of your comment, which can include any additional personal data you wish to disclose to other users of our website. If you post a comment to an article of our website, please note that this information can be viewed by others with access to those areas. 

### Outbound Messages

When you choose to initiate contact via our website with one of our advertising partners or a company in our directory, you will be asked to provide your name, organization, and email address, and you can edit this information before sending your message. In some cases, we may also request your address, telephone and fax numbers, and country to provide the entity you wish to contact with more options to contact you. Some of these fields are optional and your message can still be sent without providing optional details. 

We also collect and retain a copy of your outbound message, which will contain any additional personal information you provide. This information is only collected when you request we contact a company or advertiser on your behalf and will only be used for such purposes. 

### Contests

When you enter a contest, you may be asked to provide your name, email address, company name, and telephone and fax numbers. This information is used to verify your identity, notify you that your entry has been received, and contact you if you are a winner and/or prize recipient. 

As part of your entry in our contests, we may choose to provide you with the option of receiving information about our subscriptions and publications. If you consent to receive this information, we will collect the personal data you provided as part of your contest entry for this purpose. You can change, withdraw, or withhold your consent at any time. 

### Webinars, White Papers, and Sponsored Content

When you register for any of our webinars or download any of our white papers or other sponsored content, we ask you to provide your name, company, job title, address, email address, and telephone and fax numbers. We also ask you a few questions about your interest in the topic. 

We provide this content at no cost to you and rely on sponsors to help keep this content available to you at no charge. In exchange for sponsoring our content, we provide our advertising partners with the personal data you provide when you choose to register for or download the sponsored content, and we will always tell you which of our partners will receive the personal data you submit. 

### Surveys

We occasionally conduct surveys. If you choose to participate in the survey, you may be asked to provide basic demographic information, such as job function and technologies and products you work with. You also will be asked to provide additional information related to the survey topic, which may include personal data. We use this information to conduct statistical analyses on topics of interest to our users, and your data will only be reported in aggregate form. Additionally, if you choose to provide a free-text comment in your survey response, we may publish your response, but we will remove your name and any identifying information before publication. We only collect this information when you consent to participate in the survey. 

## Personal Data From Others

We collect data through cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies. 

### Cookies and Passive Tracking

In certain circumstances, we may obtain non-personal information about your use of this website through cookies. "Cookies" are small files placed on your computer by your browser and are often used to make websites work, as well as provide information to the website operator. We also collect information on read and click-through rates of our email communications through the use of beacons. 

We use these web-based technologies for the purposes of: 

  * Analyzing the traffic on our website and in our emails to improve functionality, user experience, and content relevancy
  * Providing you with communications tailored to your preferences and interests

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. If you disable cookies in your browser, you may not be able to use all of the interactive features of our website. 

Please note that some advertisers may use cookies when you click on their advertisements on our site. Those cookies are controlled by the advertisers and are not subject to this privacy notice. 

### Third Parties

When you interact with content provided by or about our advertisers, we compare your IP address against our own databases, as well as databases provided by third parties, to match your IP address to your company and geographic location (at a country-level). The IP matching database provided to us by a third party is housed on our internal network, and when we access the database, your information is only read by our network. We do not share your IP address with the third party. 

We match your IP address to your company and country only when you interact with our advertiser content or information, as we collect and share this information with our advertisers for the purpose of helping our advertisers make decisions about the relevancy and usefulness of content they provide to our users. We do not share more than your company and country location with our advertisers without your consent. 

We also collect social media handles, content, and other data posted on our official social media pages as well as information (such as email address and other information) you allow to be shared through our social media apps, tools, widgets, and plug-ins. 

## HOW WE USE PERSONAL DATA

Our use of your data will depend on your interactions with our website. 

How we use your personal data will depend on what services you are using and the permissions you have given us. 

We use your data to provide you with the services you request. 

### Provide Requested Services

We will use your personal data to enable you to create a member account, subscribe to our newsletters, publications, and mailings, and participate in special events. We will also use your data to respond to communications you have initiated. 

When you initiate contact through our website with one of our advertisers, we use the personal data you provide through your request form to notify the advertiser of your interest, as well as sending the content of your outbound message. We also use your personal data to create a record of your outbound message on our website for our advertisers to reference in the future should they lose your original message. This record is restricted and only accessible by us and the advertiser to which you sent the message. Our advertisers will only have access to your message for two years after you send it. 

We use your data to publish content you have submitted. 

### Publishing Submitted Content

When you have chosen to submit content to be considered for publication on our website or in our magazine, as well as our Buyers' Guide, we will use the information you provide to follow up with you about your submission, and, where we have elected to publish your content, we will publish your information in conjunction with the material you submit. Some information is collected for statistical purposes, which we use to understand the demographics of your industry and the markets. Such information is only used in aggregate and not tied to you individually. 

We use your data to improve our website and your user experience. 

### Enhance User Experiences

We use Google Analytics to determine which areas of our website users like and don't like, based on traffic to those areas. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. For our website analytics, we only use aggregate, anonymous data that cannot be traced back to you individually by us or Google Analytics. 

For information about Google Analytics' information practices and related opt-out choices, [click here.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)

We use your data to communicate with you and share content we think you might enjoy. 

### Communications and Marketing

We use the contact information you provide to communicate with you directly, both to fulfill any requests for our publications and to share with you news and updates on our products. You are able to manage your communication preferences. 

When you consent to receive marketing communications from us, we also use your personal data to provide carefully selected and screened mailings, prepared and sent by us, from certain advertisers or other companies that we think may be of interest to you. 

We use your data to share information with our advertising partners. 

### Advertising

We use your data to create aggregate, anonymous reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively and allows you to receive advertisements that are pertinent to you. 

We also use your personal data to inform our advertising partners which users have accessed or downloaded their sponsored content or requested further information on their product. 

We use your data for security and fraud-prevention purposes. 

### Security and Fraud Prevention

We use your data (including your communications) when necessary for security purposes or to investigate possible fraud or other violations of this policy and/or attempts to harm our users. 

## HOW WE SHARE PERSONAL DATA

We share your data with your consent or when necessary to support your use of our services. 

We share your personal data with your consent or when necessary to provide a service or complete a transaction you requested. 

Additionally, we also share your data with service vendors we have engaged to help provide requested services or transactions, such as payment processing, content publishing and mailing vendors, subscription and communication management vendors, and website hosting and management. 

We share your data with advertisers based on your permission. 

### Advertising Partners

We share your personal data with outside partners when you consent to sharing or interact with content provided by or about our advertisers. Where you consent to sharing your personal data with advertisers, such as when you download sponsored content, register for a sponsored webinar, request more information, or initiate contact with an advertiser, we share your name, organization, email address, the content you viewed, and any other personal data you choose to share. 

When we send you communications on behalf of our advertising partners, we will share your company and country with our advertising partners when you click on their promotional links in our communications. We will only share this information if you click on the links, and we will not share your name or contact information with our advertising partners unless you specifically request more information from an advertiser. 

When you access content from or about our advertisers but do not engage in activities that trigger further interaction with the advertiser, such as clicking on an advertisement or viewing the advertiser's information in our buyers' guide, we share your company name and country with our advertisers. Additionally, we share aggregate data on website traffic, which can include anonymized personal data that cannot reasonably be traced back to you. 

You have choices about how your information is shared with advertisers and may chose not to receive communications from third parties. 

We will share your personal data when we are required to do so by law. 

### As Required by Law

When required by law, regulation, or legal process we will share your personal data with government authorities, enforcement officials, or third parties as necessary to meet our legal obligations. We may also disclose personal information if we believe disclosure is necessary to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft, or to protect our own rights or property or the rights, property, or safety of others. 

If we sell our business, we may share your personal data as part of that transaction. 

### Sale of Business

We reserve the right to transfer your personal information in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or its assets. In such event, your personal information will continue to be protected by this privacy notice. 

## EEA DATA SUBJECT CHOICES AND RIGHTS

If you are an EEA data subject, you can make choices about how your data is collected, used, and shared. 

If you are accessing our website from within the European Economic Area ("EEA"), you have certain rights and choices about the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal data processed from the EEA. Your rights include: 

  * Accessing your data to know what information we have collected and how it has been used and shared
  * Requesting the deletion of all or some of your personal data
  * Changing or correcting inaccurate or outdated information
  * Objecting to, limiting, or restricting the use of all or some of your personal data
  * Requesting a copy of your personal data

To exercise your rights, you can contact us at [privacy@photonics.com](mailto:privacy@photonics.com) or: 

**Laurin Publishing Co., Inc.**   
P.O. Box 4949   
Pittsfield, MA 01202-4949   
Telephone: +1 413-499-0514   
Fax: +1 413-442-3180 

You have the right to lodge a complaint. 

Where we are processing your personal data that came from within the EEA, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate supervisory authority if you believe we have violated your privacy rights or applicable data protection laws. 

## OTHER IMPORTANT INFORMATION

Based on your location, we may transfer your personal data across international borders to the United States. 

### Cross-Border Data Transfers

We process data both inside and outside the United States and will only transfer your data if an appropriate level of protection for your personal data is guaranteed. We may also transfer your personal data if one of the approved legal exceptions can be invoked. 

It is important to note that the data protection laws in the United States may be different, and potentially not as protective, as the laws in your country. 

We maintain security safeguards to protect your personal data. 

### Security

We have implemented organizational and technical safeguards to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. We use secure socket layer (SSL) to help protect the data you share with us. 

If you are a resident of California, you have the right to request information on how we share your information with third parties for direct marketing purposes, as well as information on our response to do-not-track requests. 

### Your California Privacy Rights

If you are a resident of the State of California and you have provided your personal data to us, you have the right to request a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed your personal data for direct marketing purposes. Under California law, you have the right to submit such a request to us and receive the following information: 

  * The categories of information we have disclosed to third parties for third parties' direct marketing purposes during the preceding year; and
  * The names and addresses of third parties that received such information, or if the nature of their business cannot be determined from the name, then examples of the products or services marketed.

You may make such a request by contacting us at [privacy@photonics.com](mailto:privacy@photonics.com) with a preference on how our response to your request should be sent. 

California law also requires that we disclose how we respond to "do-not-track requests" from our users. At this time, we do not currently respond to "do-not-track" requests from our users' browsers. 

Our website is not intended for children under the age of 16. 

### Children Under the Age of 16

Our website is not intended for children under the age of 16, and no one under the age of 16 may provide information on this website. 

Our privacy notice applies only to our websites. 

### Third-Party Websites

This website may contain links to websites owned or operated by third parties. This privacy notice applies only to our websites and not to any third-party websites. 

Changes to this privacy notice apply after the "effective date." 

### Changes to this Policy

We will periodically review and revise our privacy notice and post a revised version to this website. Any changes will apply to your personal data from the "Effective Date" on the notice. You can find the current version of our privacy notice at any time by clicking on the "Privacy Policy" link at the bottom of our web page. 

Contact us with any questions, concerns, or to exercise your rights. 

### Contact Information

Please contact us with any questions, concerns, or to exercise your rights. You can contact us at [privacy@photonics.com](mailto:privacy@photonics.com) or at: 

**Laurin Publishing Co., Inc.**   
P.O. Box 4949   
Pittsfield, MA 01202-4949   
Telephone: +1 413-499-0514   
Fax: +1 413-442-3180
